Hey guys welcome to the new learning.
In this video we are going to learn TTID spoofing.
Many of them know what is a period of process.
So this can be used for evade the detection as well as it will be used for and some other
tactics, maybe a privileged escalation, access token manipulation with TTID spoofing.
So we need to understand what is a pit first okay, what is a PID, PID's process identifier.
So when you start a new process in Windows or any Linux or Mac OS or any operating system,
your Windows operating system will lock it, separate, unique PID for you okay.
So let's take an example, I have a Chrome open, you can see the PID of a Chrome okay.
So it's a 5-3, 7-2 as a PID process identifier.
As I said when you start a new process, if I start a new process like a Notepad.exe or any
other Calc.exe or anything, so I will be getting a unique PID for a Notepad.exe, 7-8-5-6.
This will be allocated by your Windows operating system, you don't need to do any other
things okay.
So let me view the scenario, what is a PPID, so what is a parent PID okay.
So now let's take an example of Explorer.exe, so Explorer.exe is a parent of security
health spray, the box tray and one drive.
So if I open any process from Windows Explorer, so that will be coming under the parent
of Explorer.exe okay, so that's the separate scenario, so you can say okay.
So what process you are opening from, so if I open any process from the, if I open the
CMD from here, so the Explorer will be the parent, the Explorer will be a parent for command.exe
okay.
So this is how we were Windows operating system will work okay.
If I open a Notepad from the command prompt, if I open the Notepad from the command prompt.
So now you can see the parent will be the CMD.exe and the child will be the Notepad.exe.
The parent will be the parent, child parent and if I see the parent of a CMD.exe, then
it will be going to min Explorer right.
So if I, I open the CMD from Explorer, so Explorer is the parent of the C, command prompt
and Notepad and command prompt will be the parent of Notepad.exe, if I open any other
process, any things from a Notepad.exe, then it will be a child from, child for a Notepad.exe
right.
So it will be extended okay.
So let's discuss about the PPTID spoofing okay.
Now we know what is a parent, we do okay, parent PPTID is a parent, crossID spoofing.
So why we need a parent process ID spoofing here.
So if I, I was a threat analyst working in a company, if let's think about the threat analyst
or EDR or any antivirus platforms.
So if I try to, if any, basically the threat analyst will be investigating the threats
based on the process okay.
So which process trigger that if I open some file, if I open some malicious file from CMD
okay.
So now the threat analyst know, so this malicious process has been spawned from the CMD
command prompt right, the command prompt was a parent okay.
So let's think, let's think about, let's think about on a new thing.
So if any of the other services like LSS.exe, let's think about the LSS.exe you opened
any of a malicious program.
Now the threat analyst, they will be thinking what happening on the machine because the
process has been, the malicious program has been started by the legitimate process right.
Absolutely the CMD is also a legitimate but we can do some suspicious activities, we can
execute some suspicious commands using the CMD and we can execute some program using
the CMD right.
Absolutely the threat actors can able to do that but if you think about the LSS.exe
or a MSS.exe or any kind of legitimate process, so now the threat analyst will be thinking
what happening on the machine as well as the same scenario will be going for an EDR or
the antivirus program okay.
The antivirus program and EDR will be thinking, there is a some set of rules.
If something spawned from the, if some, let's take an example, there is a word.exe okay.
There is a word document, if a word document okay.
So if something executed, if some PowerShell command has been executed from the word document,
so now the threat analyst thing, it could be some macro based things has been happened
right.
Some macro based document coming from Outlook or coming from any other platform and the user
opened that and PowerShell commands get executed that will be a scenario right.
So let's think if some other process like security fields service or MSMP engine.exe,
if some other logins or some other process running inside a windows, if it's open any other
malicious program, now the EDR we can easily evade the program right.
So based on the behavior detection of an EDR, so if something spawned from the, if something
gets executed from the Excel.exe, Excel sheet or spreadsheet or any word document, the
EDR will be dominating your word or Excel and it will be triggering an alert right.
So it's a behavior based detection okay.
So also if something spawned from the MSHTA.exe, MSHTA execute our PowerShell, so now we will
be getting a case and the EDR will be dominating that process to right.
So I already said if something spawned from some other login like MSMP, ENG.exe triggered
malicious executable, so now EDR does not know how to detect the, because it completely
a behavior based detection right, so we are dumping the Ls and we'll be getting a, we'll
be getting an alert that's, that's completely a behavior based detection right.
So in our scenario, we need to execute some malicious program, but we need to evade the
antivirus and EDR, so you can follow the parent process ID spoofing attack, okay.
I already have developed a program, it will be sitting under my repository, TPID spoofing,
you can, in this you can find the executable as well as the C++ program, also you can see
the same in the access token manipulation, ProConstealer1.exe, you can download that,
you can use that, okay. I'll be giving the, or the GitHub repo in the course, okay.
So let's go to the programs, TPID spoofing, and I'll be opening the command prompt.
Let me redirect to, now you can see, we have redirected to the TPID spoofing directory and
we can execute the program, so now we're just asking for a few parameters like, so that
shield DD command to execute and that shield DD, what parent process ID we need to spoof,
so let me go to my process hacker and I will be selecting few, one of the process.
So let me select, let me select the Chrome here, 5372 that was appeared, let me select
this, okay.
So I'll be opening, Cal, calculator, by spoofing the process like 5372, that belongs
to the Chrome, that belongs to the Chrome feed, let me try to spoof it, okay. I was unable
to do the, let me click on you, I was unable to find that the Chrome feed was of 5372.
Let me execute this first, so now you can see there is a calculator has been open, right,
the calculator has been open, so if you notice the minute change at the Chrome, let me,
let me close this and let me execute the command remote, so now you can, please as you can
see, some minute changes in the Chrome, the calculator, right, so now how do we know the
Chrome spawned the calculator.exe, okay, so let me, let me go to the event ID, okay, we
can check the event ID's, let me go to the, let me give you an idea how to detect the
parent, it's spoofing, let me go to the logs first, the system 32, so here you can find
the connectivity and logs, so here we have a set of logs, we need to, there's a separate
logs to investigate, let me show you that, let me go to, if you, if you can't forget
a system on, you can easily investigate that, let's go to the Microsoft and Windows, here
you can find set of things, here we have a system on, let me go to the system on logs,
so anyway, system on event ID, one also process creation event ID, so if you need to investigate
the parent, it's spoofing attack, let me redirect to the event ID, one, here we can see
the calculator application has been opened, and hand it to has been terminated, the even
ID 5 will be the termination events, so here you can see the calculator has been opened
right, the process create, the process create event has been there, so now, now you can
see there is a, there's a, one more event ID, the Chrome.exe, and the Chrome.exe spawned
the calculator.exe, this is the parent, parent, right, the parent command line, the Chrome,
okay, the Chrome opened the calc.exe here, so that, we have used the program, Tpid, and
the process has been terminated, it ran, and it has been terminated, and the calculator
has been running, right, so now you can easily spoof P or EDR, the behavior based detection,
and you can, you can spoof the parent, and you can rent that program, okay, this is a very
efficient to bypass EDRs and antivirus programs from a behavior based detection, okay,
so that's all about the video, hope you have enjoyed this PPAD spoofing, so every tool
still be under my repo, you can check that, okay, okay, let's talk about this video and
we'll continue our discussion in the next video, see you guys, bye bye.